TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
잘 부탁드립니다!
Please help!
보세요! 여기여기!
Take a look! Here!
이 쪽도 부탁드립니다!
Please help me if you can!
잘 부탁드려요!
Thank you for the interest!
뭐야?
What is this?
"정보 구함"
"Looking for information"
수수께끼의 메다로터에 관한 정보를 알려 주세요!
Please let me know anything about the Mysterious Medarotter!
수수께끼의 메다로터라면 걔지? 도쿠스의 마스터.
Isn't the Mysterious Medarotter the master of Dorcus?
네, 데스 메다로터에게 무리하게 로보틀을 거는 위험한 인물입니다!
Yep, he's a dangerous person who keeps Robattling Death Medarotters!
꼭 협력해 주세요!
Please help!
모든 정보 제공자에게는...
To all the information providers...
데스 메다로트 증정?!
you're giving away Death Medarots!?
-어, 말도 안 돼!
-정말입니다.
-No way!
-We're serious!
게다가 한정 생산 초레어 데스 메다로트, 이번 한정이니 꼭!
Moreover, it's a limited edition super rare Death Medarot, so don't forget!
정말이야, 초레어?!
Really?! Super rare?!
-대단해!
-나 꼭 가질 거야!
-Awesome!
-I will take one!
저런, 그런 거에 끌리다니.
Too bad! You're interested in that?
그렇게 데스 메다로트 갖고 싶어? 그런 시시한 거 따위!
Do you want Death Medarots that much? Those are boring!
생각해 봐, 힘뿐이고 머리 나쁜 쓰기도 힘든 놈들이잖아.
Think about it. They're all about physical strength, they're dim, and they're hardly useful!
그거 너 말이냐?
Are you talking about yourself?
뭐야! 데스 메다로트는 메다로트 짝퉁이잖아!
What was that? Death Medarot is nothing more than a rip-off of Medarot!
-완전 달라!
-훨씬 멋지고!
-어디에서도 안 파는 보물같은 메다로트니까!
-It's completely different!
-It's way cooler!
-It's like treasures! Nobody sells them!
그, 그러니까, 뭘 고자질하고, 그렇게 하품이나 받으려 하다니 너무 졸렬하잖아?
I- I'm saying that, tattling on person just to get some low quality thing is cheap!
조사 활동입니다! 그를 방목하는 건 사회적인 손실입니다.
It's a research project! It's a loss of society to let him be out of control.
멋대로 나쁜 놈 취급하지 마! 걘 똑바로 로보틀하고 있어!
Don't treat him as if he's bad! He does Robattles fair and quare!
데스 메다로트를 철저히 파괴하는 건 규칙 위반 아닌가요? 당신은 수수께끼의 메다로터에 대해 얼마나 안다는 건가요?
Isn't destroying Death Medarots a violation of rules? How much do you know about the mysterious Medarotter?
아, 그건...
Oh, that...
아리카의 꽃밭
Arika's Flower Garden
(en: Erika's Secret Garden)
그건, 내가 뭐든지 알고 있는 건 아니어도, 내 감이 나쁜 놈이 아니라고 하잖아!
Well, while I don't know everything, but my instinct is saying that he's not a bad guy!
그럼 왜 얼굴을 숨기고 없어지곤 하는 거래?
Then, why does he hide his face and sometimes disappear?
분명, 꼭, 아마, 꽤나 사정이...
Probably, maybe, I guess that he got his problems...
그래서 그 사정이 뭔데?
So, what's his problem?
그러니까, 사정이야.
It's his problem!
아예 모르잖아. 그치?
You have no clue. Don't you agree?
거 참, 정말...
Oh dear, well...
뭐, 난 아무래도 상관 없어.
Well, it doesn't matter for me.
어? 너 조금 전만 해도 뭐라 씨부렁댔잖아.
Hey, weren't you the one to complain about that?
상품 받자고 정체를 찾아 돌아다니다니, 좀 그치?
Exposing who he is just to get some prizes is cheap, don't you think so?
그 아이들하고 같은 취급 받긴 싫어.
I don't want to be treated like those kids.
정말...
Well...
게다가, 난 이렇게 생각해. 비밀은 누구에게도 있지 않나 하고.
Moreover, I think that everyone has own secrets.
어?
Huh?
농담이야!
Just joking!
아리카!
Arika!
쉬잇, 쉬잇! 목소리가 너무 커!
Shh, shh! You're too loud!
안 들켰지?
Did you stay hidden?
그건 걱정 마.
Don't worry.
굳이 안 숨겨도 되지 않아?
Do you really have to hide this?
안 돼. 절대 안 돼.
Yes. Absolutely yes.
-왜?
-어쨌든 안 돼!
-Why?
-Nobody shall know about this!
소녀 취급 당하는 게 그렇게 싫어?
Do you really hate being treated like a maiden that much?
그래. 격에 안 어울린다느니 미쳤다느니 열이 올랐다느니. 온갖 이상한 소리 들을 게 뻔하잖아.
Yes. They'll say that it doesn't fit me, I'm sick, or something like that. I don't want to listen to those stupid things.
네, 네.
Yeah, I see.
내가 겨우 발견한 곳이야. 좀만 더 독차지해도 괜찮지 않아?
Only I have discovered this place at last. I guess I can claim this place for my own for a while!
네, 네.
Yeah, sure!
봐봐. 곧 용담이 필 거 같아!
Look at this. These gentians are gonna bloom soon!
여기 짚신나물은 벌써 끝이야.
This agrimony is almost done for!
짚신나물?
Agrimony?
잠깐. 전에 찍은 게 이 메모리 카드에 있어.
Just a moment. Previous pictures are in this memory card.
아, 이거? 내년 또 피면 좋겠다!
Oh, this? I hope this blooms again next year!
필 거야.
It will.
그걸 위해서...
That's why...
...이렇게 매일 손봐주는 거야.
...I'm taking care of them every day!
비가 와 주면 좋을 텐데...
I hope it rains...
나중에 슬슬 새로운 종자나 구근이나 블록으로 꾸미고 싶고, 비료도 있고.
I want to decorate with new species, bulbs or blocks later, and I got fertilizers.
그렇게 손이 많이 갈 줄이야.
I didn't know it took a great care!
그래도 손이 가는 만큼 결과가 나오잖아.
But it rewards as much as I took care!
여기다!
Here!
찾아냈어!
We found them!
모자를 벗겨내! 얼굴을 드러내, 수수께끼의 메다로터!
Get off your hat and show your face, you Mysterious Medarotter!
그건 못 한다.
I cannot do that.
그럼 로보틀로 정해!
Then we'll settle this by Robattle!
난 의미 없는 로보틀은 안 한다.
I do not do meaningless Robattles.
싫어도 해야 할 거야!
You will do this, even if you don't want to!
겨우 그런 걸 위해...
What a meaningless objective...
가라, 블랙메일!
Go, Blackmail!
도쿠스, 한방에 치워라.
Dorcus, clear them up with one blow.
예, 마스터.
Yes, Master.
-그렇게는 안 될 거야!
-쉽게 보지 마!
-That won't happen!
-Don't look down of us!
역시 메다로트로는 안 되나 봐!
I guess Medarots are never good for these things!
메다로트가 안 되는 게 아니다. 메다로터에게 힘이 없을 뿐.
It's not Medarots' fault. It's just that Medarotters are weak.
얼굴도 안 드러내는 주제에 잘난 척 하지 마!
Don't act if you're cool when you're not even showing your face!
그래! 그런 태도도 지금이 끝이야!
Yeah! That attitude ends now!
가자!
Let's go!
젠장!
Damn!
멈춰.
Stop.
뭔 짓을...
How dare you...
겨우 로보틀이잖아.
It was just a Robattle.
발밑을 봐!
Look under your feet!
기껏 예쁘게 폈는데...
It finally bloomed and...
그냥 잡초잖아.
It's just a weed.
그냥 잡초가 아니야! 저기 핀 건 달리아!
It's not just a weed! That ones are dahlias!
저건 엉겅퀴!
Those are thistles!
이름도 다 있고 아름다운 거야!
All of those got names and are pretty!
사과해. 사과하고 여길 원래대로 돌려놔!
Apologize. Apologize and restore this place!
내 꽃밭!
My flower garden!
하찮군.
How stupid.
너 따위 최악이야!
You're the worst guy ever!
불쌍해...
How pitiful...
할 거야.
I will do it.
어?
What?
내가 할 거야. 걔 멍청한 얼굴 드러내 주겠어!
I will do it. I will expose his stupid face!
어? 왜? 흥미 없댔잖아.
Huh? Why would I? I told you I'm not interested.
사정이 바뀌었어.
I got my problems.
어? 사정?
Problems?
협력할 거야, 안 할 거야? 골라!
Are you going to help or not? Decide!
왠지 할 기분이 안 드는데...
I don't feel like doing so...
뭐, 뭐야.
W- what was that?
나에, 매혹적인 미소, 전 36포즈. 촬영자 아마자케 아리카 님!
Nae's charming smiles, 36 poses in total! Taken by Amazake Arika!
그, 그래서?
S- so what?
협력해, 잇키.
Help me, Ikki.
지운다, 사진들?
I'm gonna erase them?
안돼! 기다려!
No! Wait!
이걸로 계약 성립입니다.
This means the contract is now in effect!
어, 야!
Hey, hey!
데이터는 일 성공 보수로 넘겨드립니다.
I will give you the data as a completion bonus.
그러기 없기야...
Don't do that...
비즈니스니까.
It's a business.
바보야.
What a fool.
그래도 아직아직이야.
Still you have a long way to go.
굼뜨다고 해야 할까.
Aren't you slow?
그렇긴 한데...
That's true, but...
그래서, 결국엔 수수께끼의 메다로터가 누구인지는 모르잖아?
You still don't know who the Mysterious Medarotter is, do you?
기다리면 복이 온다고 해도, 그건 무능을 변명하는 거라는 생각이 들지 않아?
While they say that all things come to those who wait​, don't you think it's just a bad attempt to make up for incompetence?
테도리가와, 넌 무능하니?
Tedorigawa, are you incompetent?
-아, 아니요!
-다행이야.
-N- no way!
-Good to know.
하누멍키라고 해. 이걸 쓰면 분명 네게 도움이 될 거야.
This is Hanumonkey. It will help you.
HNM형 하누멍키
HNM Type Hanumonkey
감사합니다! 감사합니다! 감사합니다!
Thank you very much! Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
어서 보고 싶어. 우리 분명 친구가 될 수 있겠지?
I want to meet you as soon as possible. I hope we can be friends!
굼뜨다고는 해도, 과연...
You tell me I'm lazy, but you know...
메모리 카드.
The memory card.
해, 할 거야! 대체 물건으로 날 낚다니, 참 대단하셔!
I will do it! I will do it! But still, isn't that cheating, to lure me out with something I like?
낚인 주제에 궁시렁대지 마! 뭔가 알아내면 메다넷 보드로 연락해.
You're the one who's lured, so you're the only one to blame! Just let me know when you find something out by Medanet Board.
네에.
Sure.
이라고 말은 했지만, 잇키도 지멋대로인 부분이 있으니까 별로 믿음이 안 가네...
But still, I don't believe him since he's kind of irresponsible...
실은 떳떳하지 못한 거 아니야? 정체를 밝혀내겠다니.
Aren't you feeling guilty to be honest? What's the point of digging that up?
-뭐라고?!
-그렇잖아.
-What did you say!?
-Think about it.
상대가 실은 어떤 놈이고 뭘 했는지 모두에게 알리는 거야!
I will reveal what kind of guy he actually is and what he did to everyone!
그것도 중요하겠지만, 지금은 꽃밭을 원래대로 되돌리는 게 더 중요...
That may be important, but doesn't restoring the flower garden take more priority?
원래대로 되돌려? 그건 정 안 되겠을 때 땜질하면 겉보기엔 원래대로 되돌아가겠지.
Restore, you say? I can restore when I am fed up with it, and it will look like nothing happened after that.
그래도 같은 꽃이 아니야. 같은 꽃이 아니라고!
But it's not the same flower. It's different!
졸려도 참고 매일 물 주러 갔었어. 기껏 튼 싹이 시들고 진디가 몰려들고 그걸...
I went to water them every day even when I was half awake. Sprouts withered, ant cows gathered, and...
나, 절대 용서 못 해!
I can never forgive him!
거 참, 정말, 거 참...
Oh well, dear, oh well...
그래서? 어디까지?
So? How much?
어디서 어디까지 들었냐고 묻고 있잖아!
I'm asking you how much did you hear!
거 참, 정말, 뭐...
Oh well, dear, well...
그래, 다 들었구나.
I see. You heard everything.
Medarot Damashii - Subtitles by Subdiver
-아, 안돼. 더 깊이 파.
-네, 네.
-N- no. Dig deeper.
-A- alright.
아, 그렇게 힘주어 하지 마! 흙은 살짝 파도 되니까.
Don't apply too much force on it! You just have to dig slightly.
네, 네.
A- alright.
거 참, 정말...
Oh dear, well...
뭐. 이외라고 생각하고 있는 거지? 내가 꽃을 좋아한다는 거.
What? I know you're thinking that it's unexpected that I like flowers.
정말...
Well...
나도 몰랐어. 디지털 카메라의 새 렌즈를 시험해 볼 생각일 뿐이었으니까.
I didn't know, too. I was just trying to test out the new lens for my digital camera.
그랬더니 꽤나 재밌어서, 어쩐지 매일 찍게 되고, 관리도 해 주고...
And then I found out that it was pretty interesting, so I took pictures of them every day and took care of them...
그걸 저 메다로터가!
And that Medarotter showed up!
그 놈도 소중한 걸 잃으면 알게 될 거야!
That guy will realize when he also loses something dear to him!
소중한 거?
Something dear?
자기 정체 말야! 어지간이 소중한 비밀이니까 굳이 숨기려고 하는 거 아니야.
His own identity! He's trying to hide that because that secret is so deary to him.
그런... 그럼...
No way... If then...
소중하다고 하는 것 보다, 어쩔 수 없이 숨기는 것일 수도.
Maybe it's not because it's deary, but it's because he got no choice.
뭐?
What?
그는 자기 재미를 위해서 로보틀을 한다고 생각되지는 않아요.
I don't think he's doing Robattles for fun.
재미가 아니면 뭘 위해서인데!
If it's not for fun, then for what?
아, 그건, 거 참, 정말...
Er, for that, oh well, dear...
로보틀은 더 간단하고 신성한 거야! 재미가 없다면 안 싸우면 되잖아. 더욱 싫어! 절대 용서 못 해!
Robattles are something simpler and more sacred! If it's not fun, then he can quit! I hate him even more! Unforgivable!
온몸이 젖어서 돌아갔을까, 유즈루. 혹사당해서...
I wonder if Yuzuru went back because he was all wet. He must be exhausted...
괜찮아.
It's alright.
꽤 재미있게 했던 것 같잖아.
He seemed to be having fun.
어라?
Huh?
겨우 찾아냈군요!
I finally found you!
계속 찾았어요.
I've been looking.
도쿠스.
Dorcus.
예, 마스터.
Yes, Master.
잠깐, 딱히 당신하고 싸우고 싶은 게 아니에요. 오히려 반대에요.
Wait, I'm not trying to fight you. It's the complete opposite.
꼭 코쿠류하고 만나게 해 드리고 싶어요. 대단한 사람이에요!
I want you to meet Kokuryu no matter what! He's an amazing guy!
난 그 누구하고도 함께하지 않는다.
I do not act together with anyone.
곤란하네요. 코쿠류에게 제가 혼나고 말 거에요. 부탁해도 안 되나요?
That's too bad. Kokuryu will scold me. Can I ask you again?
관계 없다.
Doesn't matter.
그렇군요. 어쩔 수 없네요.
I see. So it can't be helped.
잇키, 어서 와!
Ikki, come here right now!
도쿠스, 오른쪽이다.
Dorcus, on your right.
위!
Up!
엄청 빠르잖아. 마치...
So fast! It's like...
그렇군.
I see.
도쿠스.
Dorcus.
도망치지 못할 거에요.
You're not getting away.
적은 한 대뿐만이 아닌 것 같다.
It seems that the enemy isn't only one.
3대에요.
We got 3.
세쌍둥이?!
Triplets?!
이제 우리 말을 들어주셔야 하겠어요.
You will have to do what we ask.
같이 놀자구요!
Let's play together!
거절한다.
I refuse.
-왜인가요?
-왜!
-Why is that?
-Why?
-어째서!
-대체 당신의 정체는!
-The reason?
-Who are you?
-당신의 목적은
-뭔가요?
-What is
-your objective?
해냈어!
I did it!
멈춰!
Stop!
꽤나 얼굴을 들키고 싶지 않나 보군요.
It seems that you don't want to be revealed.
그 정도로 약점이라는 거네요.
So, it must be your weakness!
그러니 저희가 손에 넣어 드리지요.
We'll take it back for you.
해냈어! 찍었어! 걔 얼굴!
I did it! I took a picture of his face!
어? 안돼! 고장났나?
Huh? No way! Did it break?
다행이야! 메모리 카드는 무사한 것 같아!
What a relief! Memory card is safe!
뭐야!
What do you want?!
그 메모리 카드를 주시지요.
Give us that memory card.
싫어.
No way.
자!
Hand it over!
아리카!
Arika!
아리카, 왔어!
Arika, we're here!
뭔 일이야?
What's up?
잇키!
Ikki!
나에 씨의 매혹적인 사진집 데이터, 안 지웠지, 그치?
You didn't erase Ms. Nae's charming picture collection, did you?
뭘 걱정하는 거야? 어쨌든 여기 있는 데스 메다로터를 어떻게 해!
What are you worrying about? Just deal with these Death Medarotters here!
부탁 안 해도 할 참이었어! 가자, 메타비!
I was gonna do that even if you didn't ask! Let's go, Metabee!
좋아! 바로 승부를 보겠어!
Alright! I'll settle this up right now!
헤헤! 간단간단!
Heh! How easy that was!
방심하면 안 돼! 걔들은...
Don't let your guard down! They're...
뭐?! 더러워! 한명이서 셋이나!
What?! That's dirty! Three by one guy?!
어? 뭐야? 같은 얼굴이 셋?
Huh? What is this? Three same faces?
데스 메다로터에게 규칙은 없지만 특별히 만들어 드리지요!
Death Medarotters don't play by rules, but we'll make a rule for you!
저흴 이기면 메모리 카드는 포기해 드리지요.
If you defeat us, we'll give up the memory card!
잇키, 이렇게는 불리해!
Ikki, this isn't good for us!
아리카...
Arika...
가져갈 거라면 가져가 봐.
If you're going to take it, then try doing so.
협력하지요!
We'll help!
힘을 합쳐요!
Let's work together!
대단한 일이에요!
How excellent!
-도쿠스.
-예, 마스터.
-Dorcus.
-Yes, Master.
브라스, 가자!
Brass, let's do this!
네!
Yes!
어라?
Huh?
뭐야?!
What?!
지금이야, 메타비!
Now, Metabee!
알아!
No need to tell me!
후회해도 몰라요.
It's your fault if you regret.
잘 알게 해 드릴게요!
We'll let you know about us well!
각오해 주세요.
Please be prepared.
보답은 나중에 할게!
I'll repay you later!
성가신 놈들이군!
They're so annoying!
놈들은 셋이자 하나.
They are three yet one.
그 말은...
That means...
하나를 무너뜨리면 전부 무너진다.
Taking one down means taking three down.
도쿠스, 뒤다.
Dorcus, on your back.
다음은 메타비 차례!
Metabee's next!
맡겨 둬!
Leave it to me!
자...
Now...
나중에 다시 와라!
Face us next time!
젠장!
Damn!
기억해 둬라!
Remember this!
-해냈어!
-쉽군! 해냈어!
-We did it!
-That was easy! Yes!
메모리 카드를 넘겨줘.
Hand over the memory card.
시, 싫어.
N- no way.
넘겨줘.
Hand it over.
서, 설마 너도 나에 씨 카드를?!
A- are you looking for the card with Ms. Nae's pictures?!
그럴 리가...
Are you stu-
그래. 넘겨주고 싶지 않으면 해치워!
Yes. If you don't want to lose it, then deal with him!
내가 이기면 메모리 카드를 가져가겠다.
I'll take the memory card if I win.
나에 씨는 못 넘겨!
I can't hand over Ms. Nae!
나쁜 생각 마. 이건 속세의 의리라는 거야!
Don't feel bad about it. It's something called the social duty!
속세의 의리?
Social duty?
사내에게는 이겨야만 하는 때가 있다는 말이다!
It means that a man sometimes just have to win!
그거라면 압니다.
I understand that.
도쿠스, 시간 끌지 마라.
Dorcus, be quick.
무, 무슨 말이야!
W- what do you mean?!
예, 마스터.
Yes, Master.
저는 기다립니다.
I will wait.
이자식!
How dare you!
도쿠스, 공격 중지.
Dorcus, stop attacking.
왜입니까, 마스터.
Why, Master?
그건 뭔 작전이냐?
What kind of strategy is that?
메타비! 퓨저!
Metabee! Use your Fuser!
좋아!
Right!
그렇구나.
I see.
나에 씨! 좋아! 나, 역시 나야!
Ms. Nae! Yes! It's something only I can do!
왠지 이해가 안 가.
It doesn't make sense.
어째서. 메모리 카드.
Why? The memory card...
나에 씨 사진 내 꺼!
Ms. Nae's pictures are mine!
예이! 어서 줘, 아리카!
Yeah! Give that to me, Arika!
어서, 어서!
Hurry, hurry!
기다려.
Wait.
기다리라니까.
I said, wait!
곧 용담이 펴. 보러 와도 좋아.
The gentians are going to bloom soon. Feel free to come and see.
고마워, 수수께끼의 메다로터.
Thank you, Mysterious Medarotter.
실은 좋은 놈이었을 지도.
Maybe you are a good guy, after all.
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
메다로트 박사에게  신형 메다로트 아크비틀 대시의 테스트 파일럿으로 지명된 잇키.
Ikki has been chosen as a test pilot for the new Medarot, Arcbeetle Dash.
메타비의 메달을 아크비틀 대시에게 장착했지만, 메타비의 동체는 코쿠류에게 빼앗기고 만다.
While Metabee's Medal was mounted in Arcbeetle Dash, Metabee's body was stolen by Kokuryu.
파괴 직전의 위기에 처한 메타비의 동체.
Metabee's body is on the verge of being destroyed.
과연 잇키는 무사히 메타비의 동체를 되찾을 수 있을 것인가?
Will Ikki be able to take back Metabee's body as whole?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 훔쳐진 메타비
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Stolen Metabee
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!